Guide to the William Hillman Shockley Photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909 RL.01177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- China: Shanghai, 1896-1897; 194 prints
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0674)
    People and carts on street
    街上的人力车夫
  - Manchu woman / large feet / 1 w/ flowers in hair, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0675)
    满人妇女/大脚/头上戴花 [站在茶点铺子前]
  - Shanghai, 1897 [Horse cart] (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0676)
    上海，1897年[马车]
  - Sedan chair into house, 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0677)
    抬轿进屋
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0678)
    田间劳动的人们
  - Stone quarry, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0679)
    采石场
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0680)
    Houses
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0681)
    Western woman and horse
    一名外国女子站在马侧
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0682)
    Chinese man and horse
    中国男人和一匹马
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0684)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0683)
    Horse and goose near barn
    谷仓外的马和鸭子
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-0203)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-1181)
    Lake and mountains
    湖与山
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 4, Print RL01177-P-1182)
    Junk on the river
- China: Shanxi, 1897-1898; 188 prints
  Shockley's photographs of the Shanxi region in northwest China feature indigenous people, immigrant workers, local officials, Shanxi guards, soldiers, and Westerners such as E. Sabbione, an agent for the Peking syndicate. In one image, a western man poses by a sign reading "Jameson and Company Engineers." Landscape features photographed by Shockley include loess mountains with cave houses, tuff, limestone, and granite formations, and views of the Fen River valley.
  Shockley also photographed mountain villages, stables and dwellings, religious buildings and figures of deities, courtyards in the snow, and cultivated fields. Work scenes depict laborers planting, fishing with cormorants, making salt, and packing coal on mules. He also shot iron furnace operations at Gaoping, Da Yang, and other locations.
  Shockley wrote about the coal fields of Shanxi and other areas in China in several articles and presentations; some are available online (retrieved April 2016).
  - Lime / Green / Shansi Chihli, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0685)
    绿色 / 山脉, 山西 直隶
  - Fen River, Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0686)
    汾河，山西怀仁县
  - Fishing, valley of Fen River, Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0687)
    河湾中打鱼的渔家，山西汾河
    [2?]
  - Tuff near Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0688.1)
    山崖，怀仁县附近
  - Tuff near Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0688.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0688.1
  - Tuff, Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0689)
  - Near Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0690)
    怀仁县附近
  - Iron furnace Kao Ping, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0691)
    铁炉，高平县
    This photo is on thicker paper mount; image is faded; one image of an individual in the photo appears to have been hand-tinted in purple.
    [C39917-8?]
  - Iron furnace office Kao Ping Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0692)
    铁炉作坊，高平县
  - Iron Furnace Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0693.1)
    铁炉，大阳镇
  - Iron Furnace Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0693.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-693.1
  - Iron furnace Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0694)
  - Ta Yang, Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0695)
    山西大阳镇
  - Woodpile in Iron Furnace, Ta Yang, Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0696)
    铁炉前的柴堆，山西大阳镇
  - Iron furnace Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0697)
    [31?]
  - Iron ore Ta Yang Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0698)
    铁矿石，山西大阳镇
  - Iron Furnace Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0699)
    [2] [C39917-8?]
  - Temple at Ta Yang, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0700)
    大阳镇寺庙
  - Iron furnace Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0701.1)
    铁炉，山西
  - Front of Iron Furnace Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0701.2)
    铁炉正面，山西
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0701.1
  - Iron furnace Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0702)
  - Iron furnace in Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0703)
  - Shansi?, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0704)
    山西？
  - Coal at Ta Yang Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0705)
    煤 矿 大阳镇
  - Coal Cart, Ta Yang Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0706)
    运煤的车，山西大阳镇
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0707)
    Liu En in sedan chair
    刘鹗坐轿子
    [21?]
  - Sabbione in Chair T'ai Yuan Fu, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0708)
    坐轿子的萨比奥内 太原府
    E. Sabbione was an Italian agent of the Peking Syndicate.
    [s?]
  - Liu En [in sedan chair], Tai Yu'an Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0709)
    刘鹗 [坐轿子] ，山西太原
  - T'ai Yuan Fu, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0710)
    太原府
  - Presents, Tai Yuan Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0711.1)
    礼物，山西太原府
  - Presents, Tai Yuan Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0711.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0711.1
  - Yeh and two servants, T'ai Yuan, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0712)
    叶通和两个仆人，太原府
    Chinese on ponies
  - Yeh Fung / T'ai Yuan Fu, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0713)
    叶通，太原府
    On pony
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0714)
    Tianlong Mountain town, south of T'ai Yuan Fu, Shansi
    天龙山 山西太原府南
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0715.1)
    Three men, two carrying cart for conveying gifts
    三个男人，两个扛着礼物筐
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0715.2)
    [321?]
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0715.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0716)
    City wall, city gate and the moat in the snow
    雪中的城墙、城门和护城河
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0717)
    Two men in snow near city wall
    雪中城墙附近的两个男子
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0718)
    Shopfronts and large building
    街上的店面和大型建筑
  - Near Yang Cheng Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0719)
    山西阳城县附近
  - Near Yang Cheng, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0720)
  - Yin Cheng, Iron Furnace Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0721)
    铁炉，山西荫城镇
    4
  - Making crucibles Yu Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0722)
    制作坩埚，山西盂县
    5
  - Yu Hsien, Iron Furnace Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0723)
    铁炉，山西盂县
    6
  - Yu Hsien, Iron Furnace, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0724)
    铁炉，盂县
    Shockley with workers
    7
  - Wrought iron furnace Yu Hsien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0725)
    锻铁炉，盂县
  - "Shih Wu P'au" near Yu Hsien Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0726)
    "十五盘"，山西盂县附近
  - Stones on trail near Yu Hsien Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0727)
    古道上的石头，山西盂县附近
  - Shih Pa P'au Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0728)
    十八盘，山西
  - Iron miner Yu Hsien Shansi, 1898 April (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0729.1)
    铁矿工，山西盂县，1898年4月
  - Iron miner Yu Hsien Shansi, 1898 April (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0729.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0729.1
  - Packing coal Shansi Yu Hsien, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0730)
    运煤，山西盂县
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0731)
    Children in a field
    田野的小孩
    [252?]
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0732)
    Man in courtyard
    院子里的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0733)
    Shockley standing in a large plot with mounds and stakes
    外国男子站在田地里
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0734)
    Two men in front of pagodas
    佛塔前的两个男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0735)
    Men and their horses/mules near mountains
    山路上的男子和他们的马/骡队
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0736)
    Men with horses/mules walking on a field path
    男子与马/骡队行走在田间路上
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0737)
    Three people in field holding rope
    牵拉同一条绳子前进的三名男子
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0738)
    Farmer with ox in field
    耕田的农夫和牛
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0739)
    People walking along a path near dirt mounds
    走在大土堆旁的村民
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0740)
    Path near dirt mounds
    大土堆旁边的路
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0741)
    Priest standing in front of tree, holding tablet/papers
    树前面拿着纸张、木板的道士
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0742)
    Women and children standing in front of a brick wall
    砖墙前面的女人和孩子们
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0743)
    Three men standing in settlement near rock piles and large baskets
    院子里的三个人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0744)
    Gifts cart with bottles and boxes
    装着瓶子和盒子的礼盒
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0745)
    Man standing on a large millstone
    磨盘上站立的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0746)
    Man standing in vegetable field
    菜地里的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0747)
    Three people by the river in a ravine
    深谷河边的三人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0748)
    People in front of a building in snow
    雪后建筑物前的几个人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0749)
    Two oxen and carts in snow near building
    雪后屋前的两辆牛车
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0750)
    View of fields
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0751)
    View of building and fields in snow
    雪后的建筑和田野
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0752)
    Men and oxcart in courtyard in snow
    雪后庭院里的男人和牛车
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0753)
    Men next to small horse-drawn covered-wagons with women (?) inside
    车夫和有蓬的马车
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0754)
    Two men in yard
    院中的两个男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0755)
    People and mule cart travelling on a field road
    田间道路上的两人和骡车
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0756.1)
    Field in a valley
    山谷里的田地
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0756.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0756.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0757)
    House in the mountains
    山上的房子
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0758)
    Stone buildings overlooking a gorge
    峡谷边的石头民居
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0759.1)
    Overlooking a village in a valley
    俯瞰山谷的村庄
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0759.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0759.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0760)
    People on a mountain road
    山路上的行人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0761)
    Mountain road
    山路
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0762)
    Mountain village
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0763)
  - Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0764)
    山西山路上的行人
    version of RL01177-P-0763
  - Granite and Limestone near [rest is blank], circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0765)
    靠近[地点空白的]花岗岩和石灰石
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0766.1)
    Loess houses
    窑洞
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0766.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0766.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0767)
    Loess houses Shansi
    山西窑洞
    version of RL01177-P-0766.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0768)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0769)
    Men and pack animals on a mountain road
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0770)
    City wall on river bank
    河对岸的城墙
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0771)
    View of hills from water
    山与水
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0772)
    Boats on a rocky shore
    多石岸边的船只
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0773)
    Group of people standing in front of houses on a beach
    河滩上的一群人及身后的房屋
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0774)
    Men with bundles of logs (?) and a hut on the waterfront
    水边堤岸上的小屋，男人每人在一排原木(?)捆旁
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0775)
    Women near piles of stone slabs on the waterfront
    水边石条堆旁的几个妇女
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0776)
    Junks on the water
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0777)
    Junks along bank
    靠近堤岸的帆船
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0778)
    Junks traveling on a river
    河上行驶的帆船
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0779)
    Shockley and several Chinese aboard a boat
    一名外国男士与一群中国人在一条船上
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0780)
    version of RL01177-P-0779
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0781)
    Man steering boat
    划船的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0782.1)
    (Women?) working on the beach
    岸边劳作的(女人?)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0782.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0782.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0783)
    People standing by the water near a village
    岸边的人群和村庄
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0784)
    Person on small raft in the water near city wall
    城墙外站在小筏子上的渔夫
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0785)
    People on rafts in water near city wall
    城墙外站在小筏子上的渔夫们
    version of RL01177-P-0784
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0786)
    Fishing with cormorants
    船上的鱼鹰
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0787)
    有鱼鹰的船
    version of RL01177-P-0786
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0788)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0789)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0790)
    水中渔船上的鱼鹰
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0791)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0792)
    Fishing boats at dock
    码头上有鱼鹰的船
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0793)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0794)
    Man in front of bull statue
    铸牛雕像前的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0795)
    Bull statue
    铸牛雕塑
    version of RL01177-P-0794
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0796)
    佛塔
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0797)
    Single house and four pagodas
    田间的房屋和宝塔
  - Slag Dump, Iron Furnace, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0798)
    炉渣堆，铁炉
  - Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0799)
    山西
    View of field
  - Shansi?, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0800)
    山西?
  - Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0801.1)
  - Shansi, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0801.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0801.1
  - Shansi guard, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0802)
    山西兵勇
  - Shansi party, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0803)
    山西行旅
  - Planting / Kao Liang / N. China / May 20-25? 97, 1897 May (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0804)
    种高粱，中国北方，1897年5月20-25日？
    654
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0805)
    Field with mountains in background
    山前田野
    679
  - Beggar Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0806)
    乞丐，山西
  - Crows in Shansi, Jany 1898, 1898 January (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0807)
    乌鸦，山西，1898年1月
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0808)
    Guard
    兵勇
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0809)
    Group in front of tower
    楼阁前的几个人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0810)
    Men eating, poorly dressed, emerging from dirt-roof hut, and woman?
    墙边吃饭的工人们(?)
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0811)
    Western woman in sedan chair
    坐在轿中的外国妇女
  - Sabbione and Yeh, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0812)
    萨比奥内和叶
    E. Sabbione was an Italian affiliated with the Peking Syndicate, offered a mining concession in 1898.
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0813)
    Men working in front of street building
    临街的摊铺前劳作的男人们
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0814)
    Large group on horseback in the field
    田野中的马队
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0815)
    Men in doorway of large building
    房屋大门前的人们
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0816)
    Fieldworkers with oxcart
    田间牛车
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0817)
    Four men
    四个男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0818)
    Overlooking a village of loess houses
    俯瞰山村窑洞
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0819)
    Several workers
    几个的农工
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0820)
    Three men near a doorway
    门前的三个人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0821)
    Man on pony near brick building
    砖房前骑马的男子
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0822)
    Men preparing pack mules
    待发的骡车队
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0823)
    Statues inside a temple building
    寺庙殿内的雕塑
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0824)
    Men and pack mules on a mountain path
    骡队行进在山间的小路上
  - Bustard, Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0825)
    猎获的两只大鸨，山西
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0826)
    Man with very wide-brimmed hat on pony
    马上戴帽的男子
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0827)
    Man pulling coal (?) cart
    用筐拉煤(?)的人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0828)
    Men in front of a hut
    棚屋门前的几个人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0829)
    雪后的院子里的几个人和牛车
    This appears to be the same courtyard as in image P-0752.
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0830)
    Group of men on horseback
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0831)
    Village of loess houses
    村庄窑洞
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0832.1)
    Two men plowing a field, one pulling plow
    两个耕种的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0832.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0832.1
  - Loess in Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0833.1)
    [山西的黄土坡]
  - Loess in Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0833.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0833.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0834.1)
    Buddhist shrine
    佛寺里的祭坛
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0834.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0834.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0835)
    Valley field between plateaus
    高原谷中平地
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0836)
    Lone temple on a hill
    山包上的小庙
  - Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0837.1)
    Mountain view
    山景
  - Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0837.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0837.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0838)
    Chinese man holding two horses, standing next to tree with wooden cage
    带着两匹马的男人
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0839)
    Wooden cage on tree trunk
    挂在树上的木盒子里的示众人头
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0840)
    Village
    村庄
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0841)
    Closeup of Buddhist altar
    佛坛特写
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0842)
    Man posing by vertical signs reading "Jameson and Company Engineers"
    男子站在两块詹美生洋行招牌后
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0843)
    Man bent over facing a goose
    男子俯身对着鹅
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0844)
    Boy in front of a wall with a bundle on his back
    背东西的男人站在墙边
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0845)
    Two men with pack train next to stables
    两个人在马厩旁
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0846)
    Group of men on horses
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0847)
    Men with mule carriage near a brick gate
    砖门前的骡骄和男子
  - Shansi 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0848)
    山西，1898年
    Man next to heavily laden pack mule
    男人和驮着重货的骡子
  - End of Shansi trip 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0849.1)
    山西之旅结束，1898年
  - End of Shansi trip 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0849.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0849.1
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0850)
    Tracks running through a narrow valley
    山谷间狭窄的路
  - Tao-tai and grandson / Salt Works S.W. Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0851)
    道台和他的孙子 / 盐厂，山西西南部
  - Salt making S.W. Shansi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0852)
    制盐，山西山西西南部
  - Shensi [Hsen Yen Ch'ang ?], circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0853)
  - Coal Cart Shansi 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0854)
    煤车，山西，1898年
  - Broken Bridge at _______, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0855)
    断桥位于[地点空白]
  - No known title, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-0856)
    View of snow-covered valley village
    眺望雪后山谷村落
  - Mine at T'ieh Lu Tzu / Oct. 26, 1897, 1897 October 26 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1140)
    [矿山，1897年10月26日]
  - Salt making, S.W. Shanxi, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1180)
    制盐，山西西南
- China: Other Locations, 1896-1899; 16 prints
  According to captions on the prints, Shockley took these images in Hong Kong, Tiensin (Tianjin Shi), Nanking (Nanjing), in the harbor at Ch'i Fu (Yantai in Shandong Sheng), and on the Wei River in either Gansu or Shaanxi provinces. Subjects include stone statues at Nanjing, merchants, a trio of singing girls in Baoding Shi, cotton bales in Tianjin Shi, and scenes of boats on water.
  - Hong Kong, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1132)
    香港
    Boats on water
  - Nanking, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1133)
    南京
    Stone statues in the field
    田野中的石像
  - Tiensien, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1134)
    天津
    Two men on river bank
    岸边的两个男子
  - Cotton bales, Mayer, Tiensien, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1135)
    棉花包，迈耶，天津，1898年
  - Chinese [trio?], circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1136.1)
    卖唱女孩
    Singing girls
    唱歌的女孩
  - Chinese [trio?], circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1136.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1136.1
  - Singsong girls, near Pao Ting Fu, 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1137)
    卖唱女孩, 保定府附近, 1898年
  - Merchants, Wei River, 1899 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1138)
    商贩, 渭河, 1899年
  - Boat in field, Wei River, 1899 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1139)
    远望船帆，渭河
  - Off Ch'i Fu 1898?, circa 1898 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1120)
    Chi'fu 1898?
    Yantai, a port city, was formerly known as Chefoo or Chih-fou (芝罘 Zhīfú)
  - Ch'i Fu, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1121)
    Ch'i Fu
    version of RL01177-P-1120
  - Ch'i Fu, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1122)
    Boats of various size on the water
    在水面上船
  - No known title, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1123.1)
    Large boat and tugboat on the water
  - No known title, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1123.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1123.1
  - No known title, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1124)
  - Ch'i Fu, 1897 (Box 5, Print RL01177-P-1125)
    Several small boats on the water
- China: Unidentified Locations, 1896-1899; 43 prints
  Typical scenes in these unidentified places include landscapes of mountains, fields, and valleys; a few street scenes; men and horses; boats on water; and various factory and work scenes, including a water mill.